
<?xml version="1.0"?> 
 
<sponsors version="1"> 
        
        
  
  <level name="Ruby"> 
          
    <sponsor> 
    <name>Groupon</name> 
    <url>http://groupon.com/</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4c769effdabe9d02a300002b/groupon_560.png</logo> 
    <description>Groupon, launched in November 2008 in Chicago, features a daily deal on the best stuff to do, eat, see, and buy in major cities across the U.S. and Canada, with plans to be in 100 cities by the end of 2010. Groupon uses collective buying power to offer unbeatable prices and provide a win-win for businesses and consumers. Groupon is a project of The Point, an online community launched in 2007 for organizing group action. Groupon builds their core product with Ruby on Rails, and aggressively uses state-of-the-art methods, tools and technology to continue to rapidly improve and evolve.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
    <sponsor> 
    <name>Obtiva</name> 
    <url>http://obtiva.com</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4c769edadabe9d02a3000023/obtiva_560.png</logo> 
    <description>Obtiva provides agile software development services for organizations that need to create custom web applications. Obtiva consultants strengthen customer teams on-site by providing specialized skill sets and languages such as Ruby on Rails, Eclipse RCP, Java, agile project management, agile and technical coaching, and training. Customers can also count on the Obtiva Studio for full life-cycle development from planning to delivery. Our experienced practitioners share their knowledge of XP, Agile, and innovative new technologies by leading scheduled and on-site training throughout North America. For information please contact us at 630-588-8622 or visit www.obtiva.com.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
  </level> 
  
  
  
  <level name="Platinum"> 
          
    <sponsor> 
    <name>NAVTEQ</name> 
    <url>http://nn4d.com</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4def7e88dabe9d2a8f004cf2/navteq285.png</logo> 
    <description>NAVTEQ is the leading global provider of location content in the form of maps, traffic and places data that enables navigation, location-based services and mobile advertising around the world. NAVTEQ’s advanced visual content, LocationPoint™ Advertising platform and NAVTEQ Traffic™ portfolio are among the premier products customers and developers can use to differentiate their location offerings. The NAVTEQ Network for Developers™ (NN4D) empowers app developers with the knowledge and resources needed to create the hottest, most differentiated location-based products. Access technical resources, support and business development services to build and market location apps for web, mobile, automotive, GIS and enterprise markets worldwide. Join NN4D for free.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
  </level> 
  
  
  
  <level name="Gold"> 
          
    <sponsor> 
    <name>Heroku</name> 
    <url>http://www.heroku.com/</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4dde71addabe9d429d001183/heroku_large.png</logo> 
    <description>Heroku (pronounced her-OH-koo) is a cloud application platform for Ruby – a new way of building and deploying web apps. Our service lets app developers spend 100% of their time on their application code, not managing servers, deployment, ongoing operations, or scaling. It&amp;rsquo;s free to get started and sign up is instant. Visit www.heroku.com for details.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
  </level> 
  
  
  
  <level name="Silver"> 
          
    <sponsor> 
    <name>Engine Yard</name> 
    <url>http://www.engineyard.com</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4c769f3adabe9d05b600001a/engineyard_560.png</logo> 
    <description>Engine Yard focuses on Ruby on Rails application deployments and operations support, so you can focus on developing your application and business. Customers have started during development and grown to millions of users without stress along the way. Start with one slice, grow to 16 slices, then to a dedicated cluster in our data center or yours&amp;ndash;all without changing your code. Engine Yard supports the Ruby community, by sponsoring the development of Rails, JRuby, Rubinius, and other open source projects. We&amp;rsquo;re here 24/7, by phone, at (866) 518-YARD or email, at info@engineyard.com.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
  </level> 
  
  
  
  <level name="Community Partners"> 
          
    <sponsor> 
    <name>Deforest Group</name> 
    <url>http://deforestgroup.com/</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4c769f88dabe9d05b600002a/deforest_560.png</logo> 
    <description>Deforest Group is a unique combination of high energy creatives, service-focused sales staff, and business-savvy partners. We take pride in delivering award winning design and photography to clients in many diverse industries. Discover… Focus… Create… Our team uses its creative energy to discover client needs, focus on their goals, and create lasting impressions of their brands through creative design and photography. For more information visit DeforestGroup.com.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
  </level> 
  
  
  
  <level name="Publishing Partners"> 
          
    <sponsor> 
    <name>O’Reilly</name> 
    <url>http://oreilly.com/</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4c769f97dabe9d05be00011b/oreilly_560.png</logo> 
    <description>O’Reilly Media spreads the knowledge of innovators through its books, online services, magazine, and conferences. Since 1978, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly has been a chronicler and catalyst of leading-edge development, homing in on the technology trends that really matter and spurring their adoption by amplifying &amp;ldquo;faint signals&amp;rdquo; from the alpha geeks who are creating the future. An active participant in the technology community, the company has a long history of advocacy, meme-making, and evangelism. Visit www.oreilly.com for details.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
    <sponsor> 
    <name>Pragmatic Screencasts</name> 
    <url>http://pragmatic.tv/</url> 
    <logo>http://windycityrails.org/assets/4c81046edabe9d3e0c000008/pagmatic560.png</logo> 
    <description>The Pragmatic Programmers is an agile publishing and training company. We&amp;rsquo;re here because we want to improve the lives of developers. We do this by creating timely, practical books and working with The Pragmatic Studio to create the best developer training there is. The stuff we produce is timely and relevant because it&amp;rsquo;s created by programmers for programmers. We have launched a new series of screencasts on various topics including Ruby, Rails, and Erlang. You can download and watch $5 episodes when and where it&amp;rsquo;s convenient for you, in DRM-free formats. Check out some of our new screencasts at http://pragmatic.tv.
</description> 
    </sponsor> 
    
  </level> 
  
  
</sponsors>